# Vincent Garcia

226 ASHWORTH STREET, WEST PALM BEACH, FL 33405 **TEL** 954 695-8653

vg@vinniegarcia.com www.vinniegarcia.com

# **Profile**

I am a Web and Mobile Application Developer with over 12 years of experience. My education and experience in both business and technology helps me deliver the most relevant and effective web presences and web-based tools for your business. I've seen the web's ups and downs over my career and I'm always looking for the next big thing and ways to improve myself and my work. My ideal position is one that solves interesting problems at an equally interesting organization, drawing on both my technical and business background.

# Experience

#### WEB AND MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPER, STORIS MANAGEMENT SYSTEMS, INC., 2011-PRESENT

I work as part of a team of three implementing and improving a web-based eCommerce solution made specifically for users of STORIS's retail management software known as eSTORIS. Implemented source code control policies and software to ensure higher quality code standards for web developers. Worked as part of a team to implement an iPad application for furniture store showrooms using the Appcelerator Titanium mobile application development framework. Worked on a team to implement a web service (REST/SOAP) interface to STORIS's backend database using C#. Duties include customizing eSTORIS instances to match client's look, feel, and desired functionality, fixing bugs and improving on the eSTORIS code base, enhancing the eSTORIS front end with HTML, CSS, and Javascript (jQuery), maintaining the company's public and support Web sites, maintaining and monitoring the sites of our hosted clients, and web server maintenance.

#### WEB MARKETING DEVELOPER, ACTIVANT SOLUTIONS, INC. (NOW KNOWN AS EPICOR), 2004-2011

Worked alone managing Activant's Wholesale Distribution Group (WDN, formerly Prophet 21) public Web site, as well as Web sites for various campaigns and promotions. Created registration and management system for company's annual user conference, involving credit card transactions, course selection, printing of user itineraries, integration with multiple third-party systems, and more. Responsible for maintaining company's leading position in search engines for various industry-specific key phrases. Managed WDN division's online advertising via Google AdWords. Implemented and reported on user activity and leads generated through the company's public Web site.

#### WEB DEVELOPER, CNL SHARED SERVICES, INC., 2001-2004

Created public and internal Web sites and web-based applications for CNL Financial Group and its Strategic Business Units. Assisted in forming comprehensive Web strategy for CNL and its Strategic Business Units. Created online conference registration system to aid in recording, tracking, and reporting of representatives attending, saving the company \$23,000 per year in printing costs related to the conferences alone. Assisted in content management system selection process for Intranet redesign.

#### Education

University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL - BS Business Administration, Management Information Systems, 2002.

# Skills

Programming Languages: Full-stack Javascript (AJAX, jQuery, Node.js), HTML5/XHTML, CSS, C#, Ruby, PHP, ASP, SOL. XML/XSLT

**Programming Frameworks:** Appcelerator Titanium, ExpressJS, Backbone JS, jQuery, Prototype/Scriptaculous, ASP.NET MVC

Build Tools: Git, Grunt, Yeoman, CSS Preprocessors (LESS, SASS, Compass), Rake

 $\textbf{General Skills:} \ \text{Search Engine Optimization, Online Advertising (Google AdWords), Web site Accessibility, Web site Acc$ 

Usability, Project Management skills

Web APIs: Twitter, Salesforce.com, Google Maps

**Databases:** Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB **Web Servers:** Apache, Microsoft IIS, Tomcat, Litespeed.

Content Management Systems: Drupal, Wordpress, Movable Type

Operating Systems: Microsoft Windows, Mac OS X, Linux (Debian/Ubuntu, RedHat/Fedora) Other Software: Microsoft Office, Adobe Creative Suite (Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Contribute)

# Links/Samples

VinnieGarcia.com - http://www.vinniegarcia.com/

GitHub account - https://github.com/vinniegarcia

STORIS - http://www.storis.com/

 $By Design\ Furniture\ -\ \underline{http://www.bydesignfurniture.com}/$ 

C.S. Wo and Sons, Inc. - http://www.cswoandsons.com/

Homeworld Hawaii - http://www.homeworld.com/

Jax online XML to JSON converter - <a href="http://jaxapp.herokuapp.com/">http://jaxapp.herokuapp.com/</a>

American Furniture Warehouse - http://www.afwonline.com/

Activant Wholesale Distribution Group - http://distribution.activant.com/

Prophet 21 on Demand - <a href="http://www.prophet21ondemand.com/">http://www.prophet21ondemand.com/</a>

Distribution Software RFP - http://www.distributionsoftwarerfp.com/

# References

Available upon request.